Connor Joseph Ludwig Staff Software Engineer

Phone: 712-830-6202 Email: cjlludwig@gmail.com Website: https://cjlludwig.github.io

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/connor-ludwig

Staff Engineer at John Deere's Intelligent Solutions Group with a history of delivering positive business results. Adept at creating and supporting distributed microservices, analytics platforms, and web applications. Experienced in leading development teams of differing skill levels and prioritizes growing talent. Routinely learns and masters emerging technologies to meet project needs. Recognized as an excellent communicator to colleagues of all backgrounds.

Professional Experience

Deere & Company, Moline, IL

Smart Activations, Staff Software Engineer

Sept 2022 - Present

- Primary engineer of novel software licensing service enabling \$10 billion in recurring revenue
- Responsible for distributed microservice development and IoT system integrations
- Technical lead for team of ten developers
- Promoted engineering best practices and learning opportunities
- Established an inclusive and productive developer culture
- Assisted in staffing decision making for team
- Met regularly with business partners to guide product definition

Smart Activations, Senior Software Engineer

2021 - Sept 2022

- Designed scalable system to support thousands of devices per month across product lines
- Created base cloud infrastructure for new licensing service
- Implemented industry standard CI/CD processes in team codebases
- Enabled distributed monitoring and log visualization for microservices
- Piloted secure cryptographic processes to protect company revenue
- Spearheaded IoT file delivery mechanism

Enterprise Data Lake Platform, Software Engineer

2019 - 2021

- Managed enterprise data lake platform fronted with Databricks
- Created data governance web app using React and Node.js hosted on AWS
- Enhanced and supported serverless architecture for large-scale data ingest and egress
- Assisted over 2,000 customers and business owners directly and presented new features
- Partnered with customers to identify optimal data solutions based on need
- Trained incoming developers on team codebases and engineering best practices

Global IT HR, Software Engineer

2018 - 2019

• Supported wide range of HR application technologies including SAP and Java Web Apps

Global IT Security, Software Engineer Intern and Part Time Student

2017

Created models for securing cloud data access

Boston Scientific, Arden Hills, MN

Software Engineer Intern

2015, 2016

• Automated suite of regression tests for mobile sales app

Technical Skills



Relevant Certifications & Experience

- AWS Developer Associate (Certified)
- AWS Solutions Architect Associate (Certified)
- Python for Data Analysis (Certified)
- Well Architected system design
- Serverless system design & monitoring
- CI/CD implementation
- RESTful web services & API Development
- Test Driven Development

- Databricks
- ETL data operations
- Blue River Machine Learning Training
- Containerization
- Agile methodology & ceremonies
- Front and Back-end development
- Presenting to customers & leadership
- Creating technical documentation
- Collaborating with & leading global teams

Education

Iowa State University, Ames, IA

Bachelor of Science - Cum Laude

Majors: Management Information Systems, Supply Chain Management

Minor: Computer Science

Leadership & Honors

2022 SHPE National Convention Representative & Technical Evaluator

2022 ISG Embedded Solutions Exceptional Collaborator Award

2022 Deere Chicago Tech MeetUp Representative & Technical Evaluator

2022 Big 12 Career Fair Representative

2021 Databricks Data Team Innovation Award Winner

2020 JD Smart Co-Creation DeepRacer Challenge Champion

New and Experienced Organizational Network (NEON) Chair

Bettendorf High School Computer Science Course Mentor

2013 - 2017